xchar.de 2008-12-17

# Xchar

**Xchar Privacy Policy**

To protect your personal data is very important to Xchar which is why we handle it with utmost care and adhere to all laws and ordinances of data protection. The most important among them: The teleservice data protection law (Teledienstedatenschutzgesetz (TDDSG)), the federal data protection law (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz, BDSG), the data protection laws relating to the telecommunication law (Telekommunikationsgesetz (§§ 85 ff. TKG)) and the allegations of the legislator at EU-level. The following Privacy Policy shows how Xchar warrants the protection and safety of all personal data according to the current ordinances of the law.

 **1\. Person related Data**

1.1 Registration data

The minimum information (First name, last name, email-address) at registration are necessary for Xchar to operate. The full benefits of the network only come to bear if the user of the network provides correct information.  
Of the registration data other users can only see the name of the user. Naturally, the email-address and password remain confidential, are stored encoded and are used for administration of the user by Xchar.

1.2 Additional voluntary information

In the personal profile, on every comment page or when uploading photos every user has various possibilities to provide more information about himself (e.g. preferred game times, hobbies etc.) This information is given solely on a voluntary basis and is meant to get easier into contact with other users. Every user decides for himself on the basis of his free will which data he wants to display.

1.3 Privacy settings

In the category "Privacy" the user can determine which information about himself and his character shall be visible.

 **2\. Utilization of personal data at Xchar**

2.1 The collection, storage, processing and utilization of the user related data, mentioned under 1., takes place in accordance with law (especially §§ 3 ff. TDDSG und §§ 28, 29 BDSG).

2.2 Why does Xchar collect, save and process the data? Xchar does it so that the social network can be realized and maintained. Every user may upload as much data as he wants and share it with other users and user groups while adhering to his own conceptions. With this data the furtherance of the social structures shall be achieved, nothing else. For that reason user data will not be used in any other way.

 **3 Xchar does not share your data with third party members**

We do not share personal information about you with other people in any way. The explicit consent of the user or legal obligation for data transmission is the only exception. A granted consent may be cancelled by the user at any time via email (fax, letter) notification with immediate effect.

 **4\. Collection of profile data**

For further improvement of Xchar, patterns of use of the members are analysed and anonymous profiles are created. Evaluation of these profiles is not conducted in relation to a specific person, that is, the identity of the user remains unknown. That way Xchar can guarantee in respect of technical, personal and organisational considerations that the anonymous profiles don't get merged with the personal data of the users (§ 4 Abs. 4 TDDSG).

 **5 Cookies**

Xchar uses session cookies for user authentification during login and as load shedding for Xchar's server capacities. The use of cookies is only meant to ensure smooth operating and to improve Xchar's offers.

 **6 Security**

Keeping your personal data secure is very important to Xchar. We will take appropriate measures to protect your personal data, including using password protection, virus checking and data encryption. Sensitive information like passwords is encrypted to minimize the risk of interception during transit. However, there can never be a guarantee for absolute security when data is transmitted via the internet. As a result, whilst Xchar seeks to protect your private data, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information which you send to us. You do so at your own risk. However, every direct attack on Xchar that is noticed will be prosecuted and is subject to private law.

 **7 Information from responsible agency**

Naturally, every user may get information about his own personal data at any time and for free. The request must be sent to Xchar by mail and must include a copy of his notarized and valid identity card. The requested information will be sent by Xchar to the address specified in the user's identity card.

 **8 Changing or Removing Information**

8.1 If a user changes his data and deletes old data in the process, this data will automatically be deleted entirely. Every user may change his data at any time.

8.2 If a user ends his membership at Xchar and deletes his account, all his personal data will be deleted irrevocably and automatically.

8.3 After deletion of the user data (e.g. caused by the user himself), it may still be callable for 72 hours due to caching-systems and the interconnection of proxy-servers.

 **9 Adherence and realization of the privacy policy**

Xchar commits to the predetermined standard of its "Terms of Use" and to working regularly at the improvement of data security on behalf of the Xchar users.

 **10 The Xchar security administrator**

Since the trust of the users is of major importance to Xchar, Xchar will answer all questions concerning data security at any time. The Xchar security administrator Lukas Schoenberger can be contacted via the following mail-address:

datenschutz [at] Xchar.de

The public ‚index of procedures‘ for Xchar is available and thus obtainable on demand (mail or fax).

 **11 Alteration of the privacy policy**

Since the Xchar platform is regularly expanded and the legal conditions change equally often, it may be necessary in the future to revise the privacy policy. The most recent version of the Xchar privacy policy can always be accessed under www.xchar.com via the category "privacy policy".
